Register of the Andrew Glaze Papers, 1948-1964
Wisconsin Historical Society
Andrew Glaze Papers, 1948-1964
Glaze, Andrew, 1920-
U.S. Mss 51AN
0.8 c.f. (2 archives boxes)
Wisconsin Historical Society Archives / Wisconsin Center for Film and Theater Research Contact Information
Papers of a poet-playwright, including drafts and revisions of plays and teleplays, a small amount of correspondence, drafts of a few poems, miscellaneous notes, and photographs.
Andrew Glaze, American poet and playwright, was born in Nashville, Tennessee, in 1920, and grew up in Birmingham, Alabama. He was graduated from Harvard College in 1942, whereupon he entered the Army, in Army Air Corps Communications, and rose to the rank of lieutenant.
Following his military service, Glaze did graduate work at Stanford University, and was a Fellow at the Breadloaf Writer's Conference in 1946. At the close of his graduate studies, he returned to Birmingham, where for nine years he was a courthouse reporter for the Birmingham Post-Herald. He then undertook a position as a writer for the British Travel Association in New York City, a post he held for four additional years.
Glaze's earlier literary efforts have been chiefly distinguished in the field of poetry. He is the winner of the Eunice Tietjens Memorial Prize, given by Poetry in 1950; and of an award from Poetry Introductions in 1958. His work has appeared in the New Yorker, Virginia Quarterly Review, Saturday Review, Paris Review, New Directions XII, and New World Writing IX.
In 1959, Glaze determined to concentrate on serious playwriting. He had, however, been writing both plays and television scripts for over ten years previous to this time, his two earliest plays being The Puppet Master, 1947, and The Seduction of Mrs. Prawn, 1948-49. To date, none of his work has been produced, but he is confident that the play, We Are All Liars, which he is currently putting into final form, will reverse this record. Nor has Glaze been neglecting his poetry, for in 1963 he was at work on his first complete book of verse, and he continues to write and to receive recognition in this medium.
In 1949, Glaze married Dorothy Elliott, had two children, and was subsequently divorced. He currently resides in New York.
This collection consists primarily of play and television script manuscripts covering the period 1948-1964. Play manuscripts, with the exception of The Seduction of Mrs. Prawn and Want Me, are in the form of unorganized, unnumbered hand and typewritten sheets, and were placed in alphabetical order but otherwise were left in exactly the sequence as received from the donor. Except for the two works cited above, the Manuscripts Library does not as yet have the final acting versions for any of these plays.
Many of the television scripts following the plays arrived in their own binders, and are likewise placed in alphabetical order. Following are unsorted draft sheets for a number of poems which Glaze worked on during the approximate period 1962-63, and the collection concludes with folders of miscellaneous notes and photographs.
Administrative/Restriction Information
Presented by Andrew Glaze, New York, N.Y., August 6, 1964.
Contents List
- Plays
  - Miss Pete, 1962, several versions, Folder 1-3 (Box 1)
  - The Seduction of Mrs. Prawn, 1948-49 (Box 1)
  - The Underman, n.d., several versions (Box 1)
  - Want Me, 1962 (Box 1)
  - We Are All Liars, 1964, first version (Box 1)
  - Who Stole the Lollipop, 1962
    - Correspondence, n.d. (Box 2)
    - Manuscript, Folder 1-2 (Box 2)
- TV Scripts
  - Miss Lucy, 1958, early version of We Are All Liars (Box 2)
  - The No `Count Man, 1958 (Box 2)
  - The Pandora Box, 1956 (Box 2)
  - The Rat, 1958 (Box 2)
  - Virgie, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Untitled, 1963; based on The Rat (Box 2)
- Poems, drafts, n.d. (Box 2)
- Miscellanous notes, n.d. (Box 2)
- Photographs (Box 2)